<u>linkedin.com/in/johanbester</u> • Portfolio at <u>johanbester66.wordpress.com</u> • <u>github.com/johanbester</u>

## **Professional Summary**

Technically skilled business professional and information technology generalist with solid experience in the website development and deployment lifecycle, able to effectively handle multiple development activities concurrently, while delivering reliable, maintainable, quality code solutions on time and within budget.

#### **Technical Skills**

- o Builds fully scalable, responsive websites to fit different devices and screen sizes
- o Develops code using HTML, CSS, Zurb Foundations, Bootstrap, and vanilla JavaScript
- o Codes sites to meet W3C and WCAG 2.0 ADA accessible compliance standards
- o Umbraco Certified Professional with 3 years of experience building UMBRACO websites
- Advanced user of Windows OS
- Comfortable in the use of wide ranging and diverse applications and products -- IDE tools, online tools and coding apps, web browsers, email clients, productivity apps, helpdesk apps, Google services, accounting packages, and various CDN, SCM, FTP, CMS, and PIM
- Strong working knowledge of social media and internet marketing applications

## **Continued Learning**

- o **Savvy Coders Full-Stack Web Development Boot Camp June 2020 Cohort:** Enrolled in an intense 12-week program aimed at guiding students to becoming fully qualified web developers
- Capstone project: In the process of developing a SPA solution called "STIX FMA Fun Finder" to help FMA practitioners search within a zip code radius for clubs and FMA events throughout the USA. Building the SPA to run with Parcel in Node, and coded the HTML5, CSS3 and vanilla JavaScript in the VS Code IDE

## **Employment History**

The Accel Group (TAG), St. Louis, Missouri

(01/2015 - Present)

#### Web Development, Support, and Maintenance - Contractor

- o Provide web development, support, and maintenance services for the clients of TAG.
- o Manage websites for 20 Community Credit Unions that collectively serve approximately 75,000 customers in Missouri, Illinois, and Kansas. Manage email services for several of these clients.
- Developed the TAG company website and 5 client websites using ASP.Net with VB code-behind.
- Provided access for disadvantaged users to several websites by upgrading the sites to attain to ADAWCAG
  2.0 accessible compliance standards.
- o Manage and maintain the daily operations of 15 legacy banking websites built in classic ASP.
- o Regularly perform website maintenance, updating text copy, graphics and code, often on a weekly basis.
- Redeploy websites to different web hosts, manage domain names, and install SSL certificates.
- o Analyze, troubleshoot, and resolve issues with web services or email / outages.
- Escalate issues to 3<sup>rd</sup> party service providers like Microsoft Azure, CloudFlare, GoDaddy, and manage the problem resolution.

**Key technologies**: MS Visual Studio, HTML, CSS, ASP.Net, VB.Net, vanilla JavaScript, Zurb Foundations CSS framework, Atlassian Bitbucket, FileZilla, MS Azure, MXToolbox, CloudFlare CDN, Zoho Suite and Email, Zoho Invoicing, and FreshDesk support desk.

Bundy & Associates, Inc. St. Louis, Missouri

(09/2014 - 12/2019)

# Web Development, Computer Support, and Social Media Management - Contractor

- Provided web development, support, and social media management, and other business and IT functions as directed, for clients like ACI Distributors, TAG, Forklifts of St. Louis, Horst, etc.
- o Assisted in the creation of the Bundy company website, the AcumenB2B supply chain solution, the AcumenB2B website, and the Wildlife Farming website.
- o Co-developed three websites for Forklifts of St. Louise (forkliftsofstlouis.com) using Umbraco.
- Wrote the ACI Dealers-website user's manual, edited video training sessions, and helped translate significant parts of the Horst website into French.

**Key technologies:** MS Visual Studio, HTML, CSS, ASP.Net, VB.NET, JavaScript, Zurb Foundations, Bootstrap, Umbraco CMS, Atlassian Bitbucket and SourceTree, FileZilla, MS Azure, MXToolbox, CloudFlare CDN, MS SQL Server Management Studio, Social Media and Internet Marketing applications.

Associate Sales & Marketing ASM (for Sam's Club Glen Carbon, IL)

(2013 - 09/2014)

### Event Promotion Specialist (Part-time)

- o Interacted directly with customers in a fast-paced environment promoting various products items.
- o Consistently achieved above 100% on targets, regularly selling out on promotional product lines.

#### RTI International, based in Durham, NC

(2012 - 2013)

## Online and Telephone Customer Services IT Support - Contractor

- Assisted a worldwide customer base via online and telephone with basic first-line IT support, troubleshooting, and incident report logging for a wide range of general and proprietary applications and systems.
- o Received many positive reviews for excellent service and follow up.

Pride Cleaning and Restoration Inc., St. Louis, MO

(12/2006 - 10/2010)

## Office Manager and Bookkeeper

- o Managed the business operations and corporate affairs for an absent owner.
- o Managed safety and compliance, insurance, personnel administration, marketing, social media, and corporate branding.
- Successfully automated business administration, curtailed debt, turned the ailing company around, and steered it through the 2008-2009 recession.

**Education** 

Lewis and Clark Community College, Godfrev, IL

(2011 - 2014)

# Associate in Science, Computer Management Information Systems (AS CMIS)

College Foundation and Board of Trustees scholarship recipient, Mmember of Phi Theta Kappa
 International honor society, consistently honored on the Presidents list of highest achievers (2011-2014),
 President of the Student Sustainability Association, and Webmaster for the student newspaper

#### Certifications

0	Agile Certified Practitioner Certification	2020
0	Umbraco Certified Professional Developer	2020
0	Responsive Web Design Developer Certification	2019
0	Internet Marketing Certification	2011